<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on John R. Lewis</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on John R. Lewis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 John R. Lewis</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes, it is possible to build rep on SO</title>
      <link>/post/yes-it-is-possible-to-build-rep-on-so/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/yes-it-is-possible-to-build-rep-on-so/</guid>
      <description>Since starting to use R about a decade ago, I have been a consistent consumer of information from stackoverflow (SO). It is an invaluable resource and I am grateful to those who take the time to ask good questions and provide good answers. I have also felt a little guilty for not giving back by being an active participant. In this post I will give some (mostly bad) reasons why I was not actively participating, what finally pushed me to participate, and some benefits and tips for answering questions on SO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Intro to Robust Bayesian Models via Conditioning on Insufficient Statistics</title>
      <link>/post/a-quick-intro-to-robust-bayesian-models-via-conditioning-on-insufficient-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-quick-intro-to-robust-bayesian-models-via-conditioning-on-insufficient-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Conditioning on robust summaries of the data in a Bayesian model is one way to achieve robustness to model miss-specification. I have called this the “restricted likelihood” here and here since the full data likelihood is replaced with the likelihood conditioned on only the robust summary (i.e. a restricted likelihood).
One of the easiest examples to conceptualize is outliers in a univariate setting. Suppose the true data generating mechanism is a contaminated normal:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storing and Plotting Functional Data using Tibble</title>
      <link>/post/storing-and-plotting-functional-data-using-tibble/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/storing-and-plotting-functional-data-using-tibble/</guid>
      <description>The tibble package within the the tidyverse provides ‘a modern take on data frames.’ It’s loaded with nice features, one of which is the ability to store list-columns. List-columns provide a concise way to store lists within a row of a data frame. In particular, this is useful for storing functional data because a common feature in such data is that each function is not collected at the same number of points.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>